RÉSUMÉ

John Krug

DoB: 12/01/1963

Email: jh.krug@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhkrug

GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug GitLab: https://www.gitlab.com/libtics

Other: https://jhkrug.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an experienced information technology and documentation professional. I've worked in development, systems and data management, support, and technical documentation, often in mentoring and leadership roles.

Most recently, after a late career pivot, I have been enjoying technical writing using a docs-as-code approach. First, at OutSystems documenting a low-code product. Now at SUSE documenting CNCF and cloud projects and products.

SKILLS

I have worked in large and small teams in a range of organizations. For the past six years this has been fully remote work with geographically dispersed teams. I have been an employee, mentor, manager, and a director/owner so have a wide perspective.

I work in agile development teams using Git, GitHub, Markdown, Asciidoc, Docusaurus and Antora, along with and a variety of enterprise applications.

Prior to this, at Lancaster, I worked in system management, data management, Oracle, SQL, ETL processes, and data analytics and visualization. I applied these skills to library management and analytics processes. I did frequent training sessions for library staff and am comfortable helping people make best use of their tools.

I am very familiar with Linux, and have used Windows and MacOS. I have coded in many languages over the years (Assembly, C, OCCAM, SQL, Lua, Python, Shell, etc.). I have written much training material and documentation so the later career change is a natural fit. I have, many times, learned new technologies, using and integrating them.

My first language is English. I'm learning Spanish and finding it difficult. Perseverance is key.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer, SUSE, July 2023 - Present

Fully remote. I'm part of the SUSE Rancher cloud engineering division. I write documentation for open-source cloud products, working daily with engineers and project managers. My primary project is Kubewarden (CNCF sandbox). Documentation tools are GitHub, git, vsCode, Docusaurus and Markdown, and AsciiDoc and Antora. As well as using them, I work with our documentation tools group to make best use of these technologies.

I provide mentoring and guidance to new and less experienced team members.

I have presented at SUSECON24 and SUSECON25, in Berlin and Orlando, helping customers understand SUSE's approaches to documentation and make best use of it.

Senior Technical Writer, OutSystems, *July 2022 - May 2023*

Fully remote. I worked on product documentation for the OutSystems low-code product set. The products provided low-code workflow development tools. We used markdown, git, vsCode, and GitHub. I enjoyed being back in full-time work in a highly technical, client-focused organization.

Library Consultant, Independent, May 2017 - July 2022

Fully remote. For the University of Leeds, I developed Alma and Primo data analytics training materials for library staff. The CC-licensed training materials website is at Netlify. The training materials are in Asciidoc and Antora with accompanying video material. The source is at GitLab.

In April 2018, I organized and presented at a training workshop on Alma Data Analytics for UK Ex Libris users in London on behalf of the British user group.

Systems and Analytics Manager, Lancaster University Library, *April 2002 - March 2017*

I had 15 years at Lancaster University Library, starting as the Library Systems Manager implementing a newly purchased Ex Libris library management system based on Oracle.

For IGeLU[1] and ELUNA[2], I established the Data Analytics group[3] to promote use of Alma Data Analytics in HE libraries. I coordinated 14 library professionals around the world helping build the wider Ex Libris Data Analytics community at conferences and workshops.

I gained an ILM Level 5 qualification in leadership and management. I received a Lancaster University staff award for outstanding achievement.

Before 2002

- With colleagues, I started a consultancy, Xinetica Ltd (1996-2002). We did well, for a few years, before the first internet crash and internal rifts. I worked at ASDA and the Financial Services Authority.
- I was a consultant at Protek (1994-1996) working at North West Water.
- I was a systems administrator at Barclays de Zoet Wedd (1992-1993) in London. I worked on the FX derivatives desk. A high pressure environment.
- During 1991, after my M.Sc. I worked at the NTSC[4] with parallel processing industrial research and the INMOS transputer.
- I was a Lance Corporal in the British Army, Royal Artillery (1983-86). I can drive a tracked armored personnel carrier if necessary:-).

EDUCATION

- 1990-1991 University of Sheffield, M.Sc. Software Systems Technology
- 1985-1989 Open University (UK), undergraduate courses at in mathematics and computing.

REFERENCES

From Masud Khokhar.	From David Summers
---------------------	--------------------

PORTFOLIO

- GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug
- GitLab: https://gitlab.com/libtics
- Libtics: https://libtics.netlify.app
- A very occasional blog: https://jhkrug.github.io.

FOOTNOTES

- 1 International Group of Ex Libris Users
- 2 Ex Libris Users of North America
- 3 Analytics SIWG (Special Interest Working Group)
- 4 National Transputer Support Centre in Sheffield. UK government funded to promote parallel processing using the INMOS Transputer. The Transputer was a microprocessor with facilities enabling massive parallelism when connected with other transputers.